Dr. Khalifa: [10:68] ... Be He glorified. He is the Most Rich. To Him belongs everything in the heavens and everything on earth. You have no proof to support such an utterance. Do you say about GOD what you do not know?
So obviously in this verse, God is angry with the statement that "God has begotten a son",
and this is in reference to Jesus.
Because Jesus himself didn't say that he is the only son of God.
Jesus said "all the righteous are children of God."
And there's a famous verse that says "blessed are the peacemakers for they shall be children of God." (Matthew 5:9)
In fact, he said "sons of God."
So, all the righteous are sons of God or children of God and all the unrighteous are children of Satan.
And this is throughout the Gospels, all the four Gospels show that.
And this is why, [10:68] ... Do you say about GOD what you do not know?
Now, If we... now that we know the Greatness of God, we can see the blasphemy of saying that "God has begotten his son."
It's like saying you have given birth to a virus or a bacteria. (unintelligible)
You know, it's so ridiculous. It's not even that. It's...
This is just to bring it closer to our mind.
Number 69 says,
[10:69] Say: "Surely, those who fabricate lies about GOD will never succeed."
In the Quran, God is very angry with the statement that "He has begotten a son."
God says "the mountains are about to shatter upon hearing this statement that 'God has begotten a son.'"
But "all the righteous being children of God" is a more, it's not even an appropriate statement, but it is more correct, it's more acceptable.
[10:70] They get their share in this world, then to us is their ultimate return, then we commit them to severe retribution for their disbelieving.
Ok. Then, we get to 71, and with the subtitle "Noah."
[10:71] Recite for them the history of Noah. He said to his people, "O my people, if you find my position and my reminding you of GOD's revelations too much for you, then I put my trust in GOD, and I exhort you to do the following. You should get together with your leaders, agree on a final decision among yourselves, then let me know it without delay.
So, 71 is telling us that everyone who advocates God faces these difficulties.
And God is giving us... why is God telling us about Noah? He said,
[10:71] Recite for them the history of Noah. He said to his people, "O my people, if you find my position and my reminding you of GOD's revelations too much for you, ...
So, this tells us it was too much for them.
Dr. Khalifa: They called him "crazy." They persecuted him.
A woman: Mã Shã Allãh
Dr. Khalifa: All he was doing... In fact, the Quran says that Noah was inviting the people to be forgiven by God.
That's all he was doing.
"I'm asking you, so, God will forgive you and to be redeemed by God."
"So, why are you persecuting me? Why are you against me?"
They considered him an enemy, just for doing that.
A woman: Same thing system.
Dr. Khalifa: So, it happens all the time with all the people who...
Anyone who stands for God, yes, we are the same human beings.
Noah had a head and two eyes and a nose and two ears. He had the same brain.
And the people around him had the same brains like the humans around us.
Same, we're all the same people.
A woman (on the phone): Hello.
Dr. Khalifa: 72, 72, Noah continues,
[10:72] "If you turn away, then I have not asked you for any wage. My wage comes from GOD. I have been commanded to be a submitter."
[10:73] They rejected him and, consequently, we saved him and those who joined him in the ark; we made them the inheritors. And we drowned those who rejected our revelations. Note the consequences for those who have been warned.
This is God's system. It will never change.
It's been happening and as we will see continuously, with every messenger, this same things happen.
And you know, even this time, I'm repeatedly reminded from a long time ago, since 1980,
that we are in a situation like Noah's situation.
Shakira: I know. You mentioned that.
Dr. Khalifa: And I wrote it in the Perspective, also.
Shakira: Yeah.
Shakira: But does that mean that the world will be destroyed?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: It's inevitable because of the disbelievers, yes. Shakira: I was thinking about that.
Dr. Khalifa: But we still have a long time before that happens.
Parivash: Ok, if it's that way...
Dr. Khalifa: Because first, the smoke has to come.
And imagine this maybe in 50 years or in 100 years.
Smoke will envelop the whole earth.
And the people will actually turn to God and will turn to this. And they will see the mathematical proof.
They will believe.
And then, God will relieve, will relieve this retribution, the smoke.
But they'll go back to their old ways,
in, say, 20 more years or 30 more years after that.
Then, the big bang.
Dr. Khalifa: Gog and Magog will come first, will invade the world, for 9 years. Parivash: And how after...
Parivash: After how so many destroy the people, and you know, how the generation in the end of the world is, as said,
Parivash: in (unintelligible), a lot of people, how? It's...
Dr. Khalifa: It's gonna be... This will happen now. A lot of people will believe, in the next 10 years. A lot of people.
Parivash: Ok, and in future that you said that is...
Dr. Khalifa: See, this goes in waves. People believe and then, the next generation, they become disbelievers.
Parivash: No, I'm talking about the population. Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Parivash: If God... the consequence they all like the Nooh (Noah)
Dr. Khalifa: Or destroyed like Noah. Parivash: ark. Yeah.
Parivash: Yeah. Ok. Just a few people, you know, everybody died. And the generation, population will be less, not what you said in the end of the world is.
Dr. Khalifa: It is not like this kind of flood. For example, think of AIDS. Although AIDS is spreading so fast, it is getting out of hand.
And I believe, it will not... This is like selective. For example, it started with the homosexuals.
Like selective destruction for the people who are breaking God's law.
When in the case of Sodom and Gomorrah, the whole society was corrupt.
Dr. Khalifa: So, God sent the angels and they turned the city upside down.
Shakira: The whole city was destroyed.
Dr. Khalifa: They were all corrupt.
Shakira: Like in the time of Lot, all the people were bad. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Shakira: So, he saved the small group of people that were good.
Parivash: Ok, but I mean, if He saved the small group, and in future, the population wouldn't be...
Dr. Khalifa: It doesn't have to be eradication for them to be killing.
We're talking about problems, misery, AIDS.
The believers will be spared all of this.
Dr. Khalifa: The retribution will hit the disbelievers.
Parivash: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: They have problems and miseries. Parivash: Yes, I know.
Shakira: Their lives will be made difficult for them. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Parivash: Yes.
Shakira: And our lives will be easy.
Dr. Khalifa: There'll be retribution. And the believers will be spared just like the believers on the ark were spared.
Dr. Khalifa: And all the disbelievers were destroyed.
Parivash: Ok, but my question is: Is all the disbelievers destroyed?
Dr. Khalifa: No, they will not be destroyed. They'll be suffering.
Parivash: Suffering, not the... Dr. Khalifa: A retribution.
Parivash: Oh, it's not... oh, oh, ok. Yeah.
Shakira: And also the population is so much more. Parivash: That way
Parivash: the population is more than now. Shakira: Yeah, much more.
Parivash: Oh. Oh, when you said it's like Ark of Noah. And you're saved. It doesn't mean that all of them, they die.
Dr. Khalifa: Not dead, no.
Parivash: Not dead, ok.
Dr. Khalifa: They'll suffer terrible retribution.
Parivash: Yeah. Because always, it was my question. If it's, you know, we...
Dr. Khalifa: How will we ride the jet plane and travel back to Iran and visit our people, for example?
Parivash: Wow.
Dr. Khalifa: You see, we need the fax machine and we need the telephone, the airplane.
Dr. Khalifa: We need these things to serve us spreading the message. Parivash: Yes, exactly.
Parivash: Ok, yes, I understand.
Dr. Khalifa: In other words, if God destroyed the United States, for example, then how are we gonna spread the message?
Dr. Khalifa: You know, so we need, these things are needed Parivash: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: to spread the message and to pick out the believers everywhere in the world.
Parivash: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: I sent the fax machine to Indonesia, for example, then, people who are believers over there.
And so, we need this stability.
And we need all these economic advances and we need the people.
Dr. Khalifa: But the believers will be spared any retribution. Parivash: Ok.
Parivash: I understand now.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) clarify that. Sometimes, we do need to clarify it. Parivash: Yes.
Humans Insist on Their Original Sin
This is 74.
[10:74] Then we sent after him messengers to their people. They went to them with clear proofs. But they were not to believe in what they had rejected in the past. We thus seal the hearts of the transgressors.
You understand this?
Dr. Khalifa: This has to do with what we talked about this morning.
Parivash: So, it...
Dr. Khalifa: [10:74] ... they were not ...
Shakira: I go to explain when he's…
Dr. Khalifa: [10:74] ... they were not to believe in what they had rejected in the past. ...
billions of years ago.
Shakira: The blasphemy.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: We insisted on it. Shakira: We made a mistake, a great crime.
Shakira: That's what he's talking about.
Dr. Khalifa: This is why I put the subtitle. "Humans Insist on Their Original Sin" Parivash: Yes.
Shakira: Yeah. We made the mistake of not believing in God.
Dr. Khalifa: Why are the majority disbelievers?
Now, if we're going downtown Fremont, the vast majority of people are oblivious to God. They just have no idea who God is or what…
Shakira: No, they believe in one God. They tell you "there is God. God does this, God does this." But then…
Dr. Khalifa: They don't do anything about it. Shakira: But then, they don't really do anything about it.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Just lip service. It's called lip service.
Shakira: Just lip service.
Dr. Khalifa: So, but the reason is that these are the rebels.
We, you and I and all those humans, we are the rebels.
So, it is the rule to be against God.
It is the exception to believe in God and devote ourselves to Him alone. We are the exception.
Dr. Khalifa: We are not the rule.
Shakira: Mã Shã Allãh. Alhamdu Lillah. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Parivash: And before, not now, Alhamdu Lillah, you know, two, three years ago, I thought all the time that he says,
[10:74] ... But they were not to believe in what they had rejected in the past. ...
It's not that they talk about the parents.
Parivash: The parents rejected the past, that we are same. Shakira: No.
Dr. Khalifa: No, this is us.
Shakira: This is us. Each one of us is responsible for ourselves. Dr. Khalifa: And when we were rebel. Yeah.
Shakira: We committed the sin. And we are responsible. Parivash: Subhan Allah.
Shakira: And I find that the majority of people, they have this feeling that if they are good to
the poor people, do a lot of good work, talk nicely to everybody and they are good human beings,
they are good human beings, that they will never go to Hell.
Shakira: They have no concept of Heaven or Hell.
Dr. Khalifa: The prerequisite is to believe in God.
Shakira: I know, but they don't believe in that prerequisite and they thing that if I tell that to them, Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. I know.
Shakira: If I tell somebody, you know "your first prerequisite is belief in God." Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Shakira: After that, even if you commit murder, that belief in God might take you at least up to Lower Heaven.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Shakira: But if you... Dr. Khalifa: Wait. Even the Higher Heaven.
Dr. Khalifa: Cause Moses committed murder. A woman: They don't know belief in God.
A woman: They don't do good things at all.
Shakira: No, many, many people are there. Dr. Khalifa: But sometimes they do. Yeah.
Shakira: I know so many people in the hospital.
The person I got the liver from, Sandy is such a nice person.
Shakira: "Oh, Dr. Kashmiri, (unintelligible) all around" (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Shakira: He's the best person. I mean, he takes me out to lunch and he talks nicely. Dr. Khalifa: And he's probably the nicest.
Shakira: And but and I, of course, I am just dying, so I bring the book and I talk and all. He's paying for the lunch and (unintelligible).
Shakira: Then, he told me "Oh no, Dr. Kashmiri, please don't keep on talking about this to me. I don't believe in God. See what a nice person I am."
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Shakira: He is rich. He is well-off. He has a good wife. He does nice things to people. (unintelligible) with the money.
Shakira: He's a good son. He's a good husband but he's an atheist. He doesn't believe in God. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Shakira: But Sandy is a nice man. Parivash: Ok. Ok.
Parivash: Ok, if they are nice and they don't believe in God because God says their work is like nullify their work.
Dr. Khalifa: It's in vain. Yeah. Shakira: Yeah.
Parivash: But I think, yeah, because God says "everything that you do, I pay", they get in this life.
Parivash: If they are good, they get in this life. But when (unintelligible) because the life is nothing. Shakira: They get it in this life (unintelligible)
Parivash: Yeah. Shakira: Yeah, yeah Dr. Khalifa: You see, they go into...
A woman: This is right, Rashad?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. They get, they get things here in this life. Parivash: Yeah. Shakira: Yeah.
Parivash: But (unintelligible) and God says it's nothing, that doesn't mean that if you do good things you don't get good things. Shakira: Do you understand what I'm saying?
Parivash: You get good things here but when God says nothing because the life is nothing. Shakira: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Parivash: Is that right? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Shakira: Do you understand, (unintelligible)?
A woman: Yes, the soul is not dead.
Shakira: No, they don't believe in Afterlife but they are being nice in this life. So, God is nice to them in this life. A woman: Yeah.
Shakira: But afterwards, since they don't believe, they are still going to be in Hell but they lead
Shakira: a good life in the meantime because they have been nice to others.
Dr. Khalifa: It happens automatically. When he's born into the Hereafter, he's born as a, with a baby soul that was never nourished, never developed.
Shakira: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, he cannot stand the presence of God and will have to run away from God.
Shakira: I know a lot of people like that, very educated people. Dr. Khalifa: Yes, the vast majority.
Shakira: I have the chief of pulmonology at the hospital. Wayne (unintelligible), he's a very fabulous doctor.
And he sat with me and he told me "ok, now, you explain to me about creation."
And he said... he's a Christian, a good Christian.
I told him everything and I said "Wayne, you know, you have to understand." And he said "yes, I understand everything."
But then, after I finished, he said "oh, what a bunch of baloney."
And then I told him "ok, don't believe me. I will give you the book to read." He said "ok, I will read the book."
So, I left the book to him.
He read the book, everything. He brought the book back in a week. And then, he told me "you talk better than the book."
Dr. Khalifa: Probably.
Shakira: He said "let's go out to dinner and keep talking to me but I don't want to read this book anymore." I said...
Dr. Khalifa: Did he read anything in it? So...
Shakira: He read. He read the book.
Shakira: He's very, he's very intelligent man. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Shakira: He's very highly educated. Parivash: He reads the whole book in one week.
Parivash: He read in one week and...
Shakira: I can read this book in three days if I want to, today. Parivash: Yeah, but I don't get it.
Shakira: But he is not... you understand where he's coming from.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Shakira: But he's an intelligent man.
Dr. Khalifa: It has nothing to do with intelligence.
Parivash: No. Shakira: Yeah.
Parivash: (unintelligible) Shakira: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: It's really a gift from God.
Parivash: Yes.
Ok, let's go back. Moses and Aaron, 75.
Dr. Khalifa: When I finish this page and then maybe go. What time is it now?
Parivash: 9, 10 before 9. Shakira: 10 before 9.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Moses and Aaron
[10:75] Then we sent after them Moses and Aaron to Pharaoh and his group, with our miracles. But they turned arrogant; ...
(unintelligible)
[10:76] When the truth came to them from us, they said, "This is obviously magic!"
[10:77] Moses said, "Do you describe the truth when it comes to you as magic? How can the magicians succeed?"
[10:78] They said, "Did you come to divert us from what we found our parents doing, and to attain positions of prominence for yourselves? We will never believe with you."
Parivash: How many colors.
Dr. Khalifa: See, people are people are people. They're all the same.
Shakira: They are all the same.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, so, I think we (unintelligible)
Parivash: Look at here, how many colors.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes. Mã Shã Allãh
Dr. Khalifa: Whose pen is this? Can I take this pen with me? Parivash: Yeah. A child: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: So, are you coming to Muhammad's meeting or Parivash's meeting or both?
Shakira: I don't know. What shall I do? I mean, I'm not...
(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: And this very long number is a multiple of 19.
Shakira: Allahu Akbar. Can you believe that? That's a multiple of 19.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok, now listen to this. If instead of, instead of the number from here to here now all these are physical facts.
All you need to do is prove that it is not divisible and all my work is zero.
It's not interpreted. I'm not saying that in my opinion, this number is a multiple of 19 because it is.
It's a physical fact. It's not anybody's conjecture or opinion.
So, if you put the Sura number, the number of verses and the gematrical value of every
letter in the Sura, 139 numbers next to each other and you put them here instead of the asterisk,
you now have a very long number which is the number of every Sura, the number of verses, the number of every verse,
and the gematrical value of every letter all the way to the end.
And you do it here you, replace this with it, we end up with this number.
I think it's 4623 digits. The number of digits in the number is 4623 or 6423,
I may have it in my briefcase, but it is 6,000 to 4,000 plus and it's a multiple of 19. That's the number of digits.
And the long number is also a multiple of 19.
Ok, now, if you, if you add the gematrical value of every verses, so the first verse is 786,
instead of the value of every individual letter, the number of digits becomes 760 which is also a multiple of 19 and the long number is also a multiple of 19.
I mean, it's really too much.
A man: Rashad, sometimes I'm so happy that I know you because I know if I follow you I'm going to go to Heaven.
Sometimes I'm scared because I know if one of us right now knows this miracle and he rejects,
A man: he's going to be the first person in the world he's going to go to Hell.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, the difference...
Parivash: The Quran says, وَنُنَزِّلُ مِنَ ٱلْقُرْءَانِ مَا هُوَ شِفَآءٌۭ وَرَحْمَةٌۭ لِّلْمُؤْمِنِينَ ۙ وَلَا يَزِيدُ (17:82) ٱلظَّـٰلِمِينَ إِلَّا خَسَارًۭا
Dr. Khalifa: (17:82) إِلَّا خَسَارًۭا The same Quran.
Parivash: Yes, the 19 is a curse for the disbeliever and a bless for believer.
Shakira: And a blessing for the believer. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: See, we have this very very powerful... Shakira: Now, you fall down, prostrate and implore.
Dr. Khalifa: Thank you. A woman: Subhan Allah.
Shakira: Now.
Dr. Khalifa: This is a very simple Sura, just one Sura with 7 verses.
Yet, the mathematical structure appears to be a physical impossibility.
Dr. Khalifa: I mean, what is... just look at this number here.
Shakira: I have to bring another paper. I...
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Shakira: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, I don't need anymore.
Dr. Khalifa: This number here as I write from right to left, or left to right, it's a multiple of 19. And it's a very very long number.
A man: This is the way to prove that we have to offer that Prayer 2 4 4... Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, I'm glad you mentioned that. Look at this number here.
Dr. Khalifa: The Morning Prayer is 2 units. The Noon Prayer is 4.
Shakira: Yeah, this is...
Dr. Khalifa: And the Afternoon is 4. The Sunset is 3. And the Night is 4. This is a multiple of 19.
Dr. Khalifa: In the simplest, simplest form that pins down the number of units per Prayer.
Dr. Khalifa: It's also a multiple of 19. 24434 and in this sequence.
A man: (unintelligible) Parivash: Ok, and...
A man: The total is... Dr. Khalifa: You cannot change the sequence. I mean, you cannot make this
4 or 2. You cannot make this 4 or 2. You cannot play with any number.
Parivash: Ok, Rashad, when you divided this number with 19, is the result is when you add up the number is 17.
Dr. Khalifa: Which one? Yes, yes. 24434.
Parivash: Yeah, I think, yeah. 17 Dr. Khalifa: Yes. This is the number...
Parivash: You understand this?
Shakira: You understand that?
A man: Yeah, I do.
Dr. Khalifa: Let's do it now. 24 by 19 is 1. We have 5 left. 24. A woman: 1236
Dr. Khalifa: Then, it's 2, then, 53.
Dr. Khalifa: 22. That's it. A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No? A woman: 1286
A woman: It's 1286. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: This is the, this is... You add this up and you have 17.
A woman: If you divide 1286 by 19, is it 17? Dr. Khalifa: That's the number of units.
Parivash: 17 number of Rak'as.
Dr. Khalifa: which is also the number of the first Sura and the number of verses in it.
Shakira: Wow! Mã Shã Allãh. Can you believe?
Dr. Khalifa: So, everything is... Shakira: God is right telling you... My goodness.
A man: Nice (unintelligible) in mathematics.
Shakira: I can't believe this.
Dr. Khalifa: It's still (unintelligible). In the Jum'ah Prayer, we all fell prostrate (unintelligible). A man: (unintelligible) People (unintelligible).
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: follow us. (unintelligible) discovered the (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: The last 3 or 4 nights, God has been sending them a lot of discoveries.
Behrouz: In this, that's what I thought, that's what I'm going to talk about tomorrow (unintelligible)
Behrouz: God sends "The Key" and it has to have all the information in it.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Behrouz: This, it might be still the minute to what we found out. It might be so many miracles. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: in Quran. There are so many miracles in Quran Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: It is (unintelligible) It is a, it's a bit, a star
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. No, but this is only a very minute... this is one millionth of it.
A man: Yeah, of course.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. You have to read appendix 1 in this book.
Dr. Khalifa: Shakira, I'm gonna use the last piece of paper.
Shakira: That would be (unintelligible), the number of the words, and then the total gematrical value of the whole Sura.
Dr. Khalifa: Thank you.
A man: Rashad, of course, we know if you bring all the leaves of the trees as a paper, it is not enough.
A man: If the whole sea will be finished by writing...
A man (Speaking another language): Tarikh (History).
A man: only this.
A man (Speaking another language): (unintelligible)
A man (Speaking Farsi): In addition to...
A man; (unintelligible) discover. Parivash: And it brings...
Shakira: This is only (unintelligible)
A man: See, Sura... I've read Sura Fatiha by (unintelligible), such a heavy book.
A man: That's it. You see, in Sura Fatiha Eyyaka Na’abudu Wa Eyyaka Nasta’aeen (1:5)
Dr. Khalifa: Where are we meeting tomorrow? Muhammad's house and then Parivash. Do you have a board?
Amir: Yeah, I prepare everything for you.
Dr. Khalifa: Cause Farima has one.
Parivash: Yeah, Farima.
Dr. Khalifa: Amir, look at (unintelligible) assignment.
Dr. Khalifa: You have a green board (unintelligible) with a chalk.
Amir: I have a ...
Dr. Khalifa: It's a white Parivash: Black.
Amir: and white paper. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, that too. Bring it, too.
Amir: Yeah, I'm gonna bring those.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, this is a great sacrifice. These are the (unintelligible) house.
Dr. Khalifa: No, I won't think about these. But I keep them here. Alright.
I just want to share with you something else that's very interesting. And it reflects what we were doing.
Because only a few years ago, we were doing everything wrong.
I don't know how it is in Iran or some other places, but in most Muslim countries...
Yes, I'll be with you in a minute.
In most Muslim countries, if you pray, in fact here in America, if you go to any mosque and pray behind
any Imam, you will never hear Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1).
Is this true? You never hear it. And at the end of Al-Fãtehah, you hear Ameen. Long, very long Ameen.
If you go to Mecca, for example, if you use Mecca as an example, you never hear Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1),
behind the Imam, never. I've been there quite a few times.
Dr. Khalifa: And after Al-Fãtehah, you hear a very long Ameen, which is, does not, it's not an Arabic word, it's not a Quranic word.
A man: What does it mean exactly, Ameen?
Dr. Khalifa: This is Satan's word. Shakira: Amen.
Dr. Khalifa: It is Satan's word, as I'm gonna show you now.
What Satan did, we were doing this.
I was doing this 20 years ago.
Everything we were doing was wrong.
This is God's blessing on us.
And if you read Sura 65, verse 11, God says "He's sending a messenger to lead the believers
"who are righteous out of darkness into the light."
I mean, we were believers, and we were righteous, but we were doing everything wrong.
And then God, out of His mercy, sent to us all these corrections.
So, I wanna share with you what the Muslims are doing in most countries, and I'm gonna use Mecca as an example.
"Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem", the gematrical value is 786.
Most of us know this, right?
See, how big it is?
So, they remove that, minus.
Pardon?
Yes.
(unintelligible)
Shakira, all those like 786 and they never let us do that.
They remove Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1).
You never hear.
And they add Ameen. Ameen is 102. So, plus 102.
Now, this is Satan's system, to remove the name of God.
Dr. Khalifa: In fact, in the last issue of the Perspective, I reproduced a copy from their books of jurisprudence,
Dr. Khalifa: saying that Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1)..., my hair stands up. Listen to this. A woman: Makruh (مکروه).
Dr. Khalifa: They call it Makruh (مکروه).
It's Satan.
Dr. Khalifa: The name of God.
Dr. Khalifa: who (unintelligible) this. Shakira: Makruh (مکروه). A woman: Oh, my God.
Dr. Khalifa: This is in the books of Shari'a.
Dr. Khalifa: The books of jurisprudence.
Shakira: They never say "Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1)."
Dr. Khalifa: This is why they do not say "Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1)."
Dr. Khalifa: Now, they don't really mean to say that it is hated.
But they set up, they set up the practices and...
A woman: I'm sorry, forgive me.
Dr. Khalifa: It's alright, we're waiting for you.
Dr. Khalifa: In the books of jurisprudence, they divide the duties of the Muslim into Fard,
which means obligatory, Wajib, which means duty, Sunnah, which is maybe you can do it,
Makruh, which you better not do it, and Haram, means forbidden. So, it just happened that way.
So, when they came to Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1), it fell under the category of Makruh.
Without realizing it, Sheytan (Satan) made them say that the name of God is hated, Makruh.
So, they do not say this and they add Ameen, 102. You're gonna miss the punchline.
Dr. Khalifa: What is the net result of this?
Shakira: You sent me this already, I know it.
Dr. Khalifa: Uh-oh, okay.
Dr. Khalifa: Huh?
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: What is that?
Dr. Khalifa: No, the product is 684. Shakira: No, it...
Dr. Khalifa: This is 4, 8, 6.
Parivash: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: 684. It's a multiple of 19. You know what it is?
Al-Quran Al-Karim (القُرْءَانٌۭ الكَرِيم) This is the gematrical value of the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: And this is minus.
A man: Allahu Akbar
Dr. Khalifa: So, the (unintelligible) Quran. Shakira: (unintelligible) the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, 684.
Shakira: the gematrical value of...
Dr. Khalifa: minus Bismillah plus Ameen, 102. It's exactly the value of the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: When you lose the key,...
Shakira: Allahu Akbar Parivash: Allahu Akbar Dr. Khalifa: Wait, you haven't heard anything yet.
Dr. Khalifa: When you lose the key, you can't enter, can you?
Dr. Khalifa: You cannot enter the Quran. Now,... A man: But you see, while the Imam is offering the Prayer,
A man: he must be saying Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1).
Dr. Khalifa: No, he doesn't. In fact, I went to them and I asked a number of them.
I said "why don't you say Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1)? This is the most important verse in the Quran."
He said "I say it secretly."
A man: Secretly, must be said. Dr. Khalifa: He doesn't.
Shakira: No.
Dr. Khalifa: He doesn't. A man: He must say أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1)
Dr. Khalifa: No, we don't say أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ not in the, not in Al-Fãtehah. A woman: That's not in the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: Outside, well.
A man: What? Dr. Khalifa: But you see
Dr. Khalifa: the way they do it is,
proves that they don't recite. He just said this, that "I say it secretly", just to answer me, because I was bugging him or just to send me away.
He said "I say it secretly."
And I said "No, you don't, because you say, and I tend to say,
and I turned to say "Allahu Akbar. Al hamdu Lillahi Rabbil ‘Alameen (1:2)." So, there is no time to say it secretly or loud.
And then, I have recordings of their prayer.
"Allahu Akbar. Al hamdu Lillahi Rabbil ‘Alameen (1:2)."
Dr. Khalifa: So, where is Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1)? A man: Without Niyat, without Niyat (intention), we cannot start prayer like that.
Dr. Khalifa: No, he does the Niyat. He does the Niyat. A man: (unintelligible)
A woman: But in Mecca, they do.
Dr. Khalifa: He does the Niyat and "أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ"
and everything. Then, he starts saying "Allahu Akbar"
and then immediately, "Al hamdu Lillahi Rabbil ‘Alameen (1:2)." So, they don't say it secretly. A man: That's wrong.
A man: Could you please repeat that again for Ziba? She didn't understand it.
Dr. Khalifa: You don't understand it?
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1)
You don't hear it when you pray in Mecca or in most mosques.
You don't hear it at all.
Satan talked them into cancelling it.
The gematrical value of Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem is 786.
So, it's minus 786.
And they add at the end, also Satan did that.
They have this non-Quranic word "Ameen", which is 102.
So, minus 786 plus 102, the net result is minus 684, which is the value of the Quran.
And it's a multiple of 19.
So, what God is telling us is, they lose, when they lose the key, they lose the whole Quran. They have no access to the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: Did you hear anybody say "the Quran is very difficult"?
Shakira: It's so easy.
Dr. Khalifa: Because God...
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Now, God says "I made the Quran easy."
Shakira: Easy. It is so easy.
Dr. Khalifa: And God repeats it.
But it is easy for the believers.
Dr. Khalifa: It is impossible for the disbelievers.
Shakira: So difficult for me 4 months ago. Now, it is very easy. Dr. Khalifa: And this is one of the reasons here.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, do you remember the verse of the Quran that says
"How come they do not understand the Quran? Do they have locks on their hearts or minds?"
(47:24) أَفَلَا يَتَدَبَّرُونَ ٱلْقُرْءَانَ أَمْ عَلَىٰ قُلُوبٍ أَقْفَالُهَآ
Dr. Khalifa: Qefl... Aqfal is the plural of Qefl. Is this in Farsi, also?
A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Really?!
(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, wow!
A man: The pronunciation is different.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, what is the name of this Sura?
Dr. Khalifa: The Key.
A woman: Yeah. Shakira: The Key.
Dr. Khalifa: We have Key and Qefl.
A woman: Yes.
Shakira: So, that is the key. Al-Fãtehah is the key. Dr. Khalifa: It just fits perfectly.
Shakira: So, we need to open that lock. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: I'm sorry.
Dr. Khalifa: So, the...
Parivash: Yeah, and then...
Dr. Khalifa: No, that's beautiful. Yeah.
Parivash: (unintelligible)
A man: I didn't mean difficult. I meant to say the depth of Quran, to understand.
Dr. Khalifa: No, but see, God made it easy. And He repeats it many times. He said
(54:32) وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا ٱلْقُرْءَانَ لِلذِّكْرِ
I made the Quran easy. I made the Quran easy.
Dr. Khalifa: And in many other places.
Parivash: When she started the Quran, she didn't know even English and no Arabic. Not even English. A woman: Exactly.
Parivash: And she's, Mã Shã Allãh, she understands better than all of (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Didn't look, didn't look Japanese to you.
Dr. Khalifa: What's your question again? Parivash: Yes, one year.
A woman: (unintelligible) 17.
Dr. Khalifa: These are the 17 units of Contact Prayers that we are required to do every day.
A woman: Why 17, why (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: See, we do 2 in the morning, 4 in the noon, 4 afternoon, 3 in the afternoon, and 4 at night.
But the number of 17 is probably significant because it has the number of the first Sura, the Key, and the number of verses in it, 1 and 7.
Also, we have a special Prayer in the week that is 2 units. If you add that to 17, you get 19. So,...
Shakira: On Friday, we do 2.
A man: But minus 2, the Farz (duty) is gone. Zohr (Noon), the Farz is gone. A woman: Number of Farz is (unintelligible)
Shakira: No.
A man: What (unintelligible)? It's there?
Shakira: No. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: That's the total number of...
Dr. Khalifa: That's the total number. By the way, if you...
A man: Of that, of that I'm telling you.
(unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Sura
Dr. Khalifa: or the number of verse next to 786, you have a multiple of 19.
Shakira: But I do 2 Khutba.
Shakira: But it's still Farz.
A man: 2 Farz. That is it, then.
Shakira: And I do 2 Farz. Dr. Khalifa: It is very...
A man: And 2 Farz is there.
A man: Why? Shakira: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Put 1 next to it.
Shakira: I do 2 Salat, and 2 Khutba. That's 4. Dr. Khalifa: 178... (unintelligible).
A man: But it's 2. You're not offering the 4 after (unintelligible)? Shakira: No.
A man: That's it. That's (unintelligible) Shakira: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So now, we have mathematical proof for the number of Rak'as, and what to say.
Dr. Khalifa: You know, we used to read Quran after Al-Fãtehah.
A man: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: But you're not supposed to do that.
Dr. Khalifa: Because this will destroy the mathematical structure of it. Shakira: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: And the...
A man: (unintelligible) Parivash: (unintelligible) jaan (dear), did you get it? A woman: No.
Shakira: They didn't get it.
Dr. Khalifa: This flood, this flood of miracles is coming because I'm working on the new translation.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm at Sura 1. A woman: (unintelligible)
Shakira: You know, I think you should also talk about Millat-e-Ibrahim (مِّلَّةَ إِبْرَٰهِيمَ) because even without this, Mã Shã Allãh, we have to...
Shakira: We already had proof because of the Millat-e-Ibrahim (مِّلَّةَ إِبْرَٰهِيمَ). Can you tell us? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: See, the proper number of units and so on? Shakira: No, because the Salats are not mentioned specifically in the Quran, but before that we are supposed to follow the religion of Ibrahim.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Shakira: So, we already know that that is what we have to do.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. The Prayer came to us through the prophet Ibrahim. It was practiced before the prophet Muhammad.
And the universal acceptance is a sign that the number of units was correct.
But we were at a loss as to what exactly should we say in it.
You know, because people are reading Al-Fãtehah and then reading (112:1) قُلْ هُوَ ٱللَّهُ أَحَدٌ
(108:1) إِنَّآ أَعْطَيْنَـٰكَ ٱلْكَوْثَرَ
But then, when you think about it logically, when you read The Key, you are saying
Eyyaka Na’abudu Wa Eyyaka Nasta’aeen (1:5)
Only You, we worship; Only You, we ask for help.
So, obviously we are speaking with God.
We're calling God "Only You, God, we worship; Only You, we ask for help." And then we turn around and say
(108:1) إِنَّآ أَعْطَيْنَـٰكَ ٱلْكَوْثَرَ
We gave you a lot of bounty.
It doesn't make sense.
So, it's only The Key that is required.
Shakira: (113:1) قُلْ أَعُوذُ بِرَبِّ ٱلْفَلَقِ I liked that. A woman: (109:1) قُلْ يَـٰٓأَيُّهَا ٱلْكَـٰفِرُونَ
Shakira: (109:1) قُلْ يَـٰٓأَيُّهَا ٱلْكَـٰفِرُونَ (109:2) لَآ أَعْبُدُ مَا تَعْبُدُونَ (109:3) وَلَآ أَنتُمْ عَـٰبِدُونَ مَآ أَعْبُدُ
Shakira: You worship... we worship... What we worship... you do what you want.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Shakira: The meaning of father.
Dr. Khalifa: These are among all the innovations that were added in 1400 years. It's just too many innovations.
And it is God's Mercy that He's helping us remove all these now.
So, what we're doing here is take Islam to the original Islam, the way it came to the prophet Muhammad.
Consolidate and purify are the two key words.
A man: A while ago, you were talking about Jesus Christ.
Somewhere in Quran, it says that before you die, you have to believe in him, too.
A man: Is that true?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, of course. So, we have to believe in all the messengers.
A man: All them, not only him, all of them? A man: All the messengers. Dr. Khalifa: All of them.
Parivash: Yeah, but they... A man: Oh.
Dr. Khalifa: Do you believe that Sãleh... Behrouz: I've seen one,
Behrouz: One verse that says "only Jesus." Parivash: Yeah, but they say "why specially God say
Parivash: "that you have to believe in Jesus before you die?" Behrouz: Before you die.
Parivash: "if you mention, it's a show of the name of Jesus."
Dr. Khalifa: Well, like any other, like any other messenger.
Behrouz: So, there is no difference?
A woman: No.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no difference. Shakira: What is that verse and Sura?
A man: You have to believe all the messengers. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: You don't remember?
Dr. Khalifa: If God tells you that Sãleh is a messenger, do you believe Him?
Behrouz: Yes, sure. So? But I mean that particular verse...
Dr. Khalifa: ...does not... When you say something specific, it does not exclude anything else. Behrouz: Right. Right.
A woman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Like the people who say "Do not go to the Prayer drunk, means you drink every other time."
Dr. Khalifa: It's not like... it's not...
A man: Sir, but what about the drink? So, is it Haram (Forbidden) by Quran?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, absolutely.
A man: Which verse?
Dr. Khalifa: Quite a few. In Sura 5, verse 91 for example, it's a straightforward command not to come close to gambling and alcohol.
A man: Thank you. Dr. Khalifa: Sure.
Dr. Khalifa: Don't come close.
Dr. Khalifa: It's a very strong prohibition.
A man: But you see the prohibition...
Dr. Khalifa: This is what God told Adam and Eve. God told Adam and Eve "Don't come close to this tree."
Dr. Khalifa: Look where we are now.
A man: We are enjoying this affair. It's alright.
Dr. Khalifa: Pardon?
A man: It is alright.
Dr. Khalifa: What is alright?
A man: Ok. We are still enjoying in this world.
Dr. Khalifa: I don't understand.
A man: Well, in this world, God has created this world for Adam and Hawa (Eve) and we are enjoying this world.
Dr. Khalifa: No, but this is a curse. This world is bad. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: It would better to be back. Shakira: (unintelligible) that God created. A man: This is the place where Moses,
A man: prophet Muhammad, this sort of Nabi has come, Rasul has come. How is curse?
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, it's very bad. This is a very bad world. See, we are now in the larva. Shakira: This is why we are created.
Dr. Khalifa: We're in the larva fold. Yeah.
A man: You see, sir, the people are eating the meat here, which is not killed in the name of God.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: That is Haram (Forbidden), absolutely..
Shakira: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Can we eat the meat in Safeway market?
Shakira: You can eat the meat from the Safeway. I told you multiple times. A man: How can we eat?
A man: In the Quran, the verse says, only we can eat the meat which is killed in the name of God.
Dr. Khalifa: No, it doesn't say that. It says "Do not eat meat that is dedicated to other than God."
Dr. Khalifa: There's a difference.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. There's pork...There are four meats that are specifically prohibited in the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Animals that die of themselves, without human interference.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: That's Haram (Forbidden).
A man: That's the meat which is not killed in the name of God?
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no. Wait, wait. Shakira: No. No. A man: Other than God. A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, dedicated to other than God.
Dr. Khalifa: Still, you have to watch the words.
A woman: We have to be very careful. Dr. Khalifa: Because this is very important.
Dr. Khalifa: Because God makes... A woman: That's why they make mistakes.
Dr. Khalifa: God makes this disobedience of the dietary laws tantamount to idol worship, because there is some other god who told us something else.
Okay, so let's go. These four are consistently prohibited in the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: Number 1, animals that die of themselves. Number 2 is running blood. You can put it in a glass.
A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: You can't drink it or cook it or anything.
Number 3 is the meat of pigs.
Number 4 is animals dedicated to other than God.
So, what you do in the Safeway market is you stand in front of the meat and ask "did this animal die without human interference?"
"No."
"Is this meat of pig?" "No."
"Is it running blood?" "No."
"Was it dedicated to Jesus?" "No." Therefore, it is okay.
Dr. Khalifa: It doesn't belong in the four categories. Shakira: You can put it in your mouth and take it to Heaven.
Dr. Khalifa: But when you eat it, you mention the name of God on it.
So, why do we Halal it? What is it, Halal (Permitted)? Shakira: Satan.
Dr. Khalifa: That's another innovation. Shakira: Satan.
It's Halal (Permitted). Unless it is one of these four, it is Haram (Forbidden).
These four are Haram.
Dr. Khalifa: Nothing else.
Dr. Khalifa: And God is very strict. A man: What else is Haram?
Dr. Khalifa: Alcohol, gambling, a whole bunch. Adultery, murder, drugs. Shakira: Drugs, adultery.
Behrouz: Could you tell her if jackpot is okay or not? 25-cent jackpot.
Dr. Khalifa: Haram.
Dr. Khalifa: No.
A man: You know about the liquor, about the wine, about the spirit. Dr. Khalifa: They're both Haram.
A man: The word Haram, like for the swill, like for the food, blood, been used by Quran.
A man: It is not being used for Sharab (wine). Shakira: It uses the word prohibited.
A man: It is... you see that (unintelligible). Shakira: That's not forbidden.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no. No, no. There are many, many different words used to prohibit things. Like I said...
A man: I understand, but we are as...
A man: Haram is used, like swear Dr. Khalifa: However, any of...
A man: that sort of things, which God has used for the word Haram.
Dr. Khalifa: But God uses the strongest prohibition when it comes to alcohol and gambling. God uses the strongest prohibition in the Quran.
A man: I like it. It's the strongest prohibition, the word Haram. Dr. Khalifa: Because God says it is...
Dr. Khalifa: God says... Behrouz: So, why do we use... Ok. The reason is (unintelligible)
Behrouz: the word is so important to us. This is how we think about it. But there are other words that is much much...
A man: It's my thinking... You see, being a Muslim, I'm... I've learned many Muslims are drinking.
Behrouz: No, I'm sorry. Let me finish my point. My point is, this word to you and to us is very strong, Haram.
But he's saying there are other words that are much stronger than Haram that we don't know.
Behrouz: But all we know is word Haram. Dr. Khalifa: I can repeat it for you.
Dr. Khalifa: God calls alcohol and gambling in Arabic,
(5:90) رِجْسٌۭ مِّنْ عَمَلِ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ
It is an abomination and the work of the devil.
So, it is very, very strong prohibition. Very strong Haram (Forbidden).
In 5:91.
Parivash: Alhamdu Lillah.
And then, He says, (5:90) فَٱجْتَنِبُوهُ you shall avoid them.
That's a commandment from God.
Dr. Khalifa: And then, the choice is ours in the end. I can still drink if I want to and if I'm willing to pay the price.
Behrouz: What is the price?
Dr. Khalifa: Exile from God.
Dr. Khalifa: Eternal Hell.
A man: Sir, can you drink one cup? (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) repent. Yes. Shakira: No, no.
A man: In the early days of Islam, the people used to come for the Prayer (unintelligible) they were drunk. Dr. Khalifa: If you don't, If you don't repent.
Shakira: You have to repent, I know. If you don't repent,...
A man: He said...
Dr. Khalifa: I don't know. The Quran says (unintelligible) you know. The Quran says "repentance is not accepted from those who sin until the death comes to them. Then, they say 'now, I repent.'"
Specifically, the Quran says that. Sura 3.
Dr. Khalifa: There's the answer. A man: No cheating.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Praivash: Excuse me. One thing, this is Haram also it's for the, if he's in Shia, they have Nazr (pledge/vow), we, we
A man: sacrifice Parivash: kill the, sacrifice the animals in the name of Abal Fazl (ابو الفضل). It's very common in my country. Abal Fazl (ابو الفضل), Ali.
Dr. Khalifa: That is Haram.
Parivash: This is Haram. Yeah. A man: Haram. Haram.
A man: (unintelligible) and it's Haram. Praivash: Yeah, Mã Shã Allãh.
Shakira: But because it is Shia he says it. Parivash: Mã Shã Allãh. Dr. Khalifa: Mahdi.
Shakira: But the Shia says the same to the people (unintelligible). A man: Shia
A man: Shias, they are doing Nazr-o-Niyaz (vows and supplications), but we don't do this sort of thing.. Yes, sir.
A man: The question was saying that the game of... this is something that I've been thinking about the time to...
Basically, every time we talk about the things that we do like praying and charity and all those things
and it's to grow, to improve our soul, to increase our soul.
And God doesn't put anyone in Hell (unintelligible) increasing our soul.
And so, so, what happens basically?
A man: If we sin, our soul shrink?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes. A man: (unintelligible)
A man: I haven't, I haven't seen that.
A man: It says, because it looks like, I mean, I've come to realize that basically there is no sin except, except Shirk (idol worship).
A man: This is the only sin that God doesn't ... Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: It is not forgivable, yeah, if maintained until death.
A man: Anything else... I haven't seen it... If you do good things, you improve. Or if you do bad things, your soul will shrink. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: In fact, your soul becomes smaller. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. No. Yes. Yes, the Quran says that.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. It says, there is a rule in the Quran that says,
(11:114) إِنَّ ٱلْحَسَنَـٰتِ يُذْهِبْنَ ٱلسَّيِّـَٔاتِ
You understand this? Can I say it in Arabic?
Parivash, Can you translate this?
(11:114) إِنَّ ٱلْحَسَنَـٰتِ يُذْهِبْنَ ٱلسَّيِّـَٔاتِ
Parivash: In English or Farsi?
Dr. Khalifa: Any way you want.
Parivash (Speaking Farsi): Good works compensates for the bad works. Meaning that the bad works...
Parivash: Yeah. You do the righteous and good things disappear the bad things.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. So, there is a plus and minus. They balance each other.
A man: So basically, the bad things improve which is...
Dr. Khalifa: They will reduce your credit and your credit will reduce the discredit.
Dr. Khalifa: It's just, it's just like accounting, plus and minus.
A man: Rashad, even though (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: And there is a net result.
A man: Even though you drink alcohol and give charity, it's going to be plus minus? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. You drink alcohol, your soul will shrink. And you give to charity, your soul will grow.
A man: So, you say the same thing?
Dr. Khalifa: Pardon?
A woman: The people who pray would never do that.
Dr. Khalifa: Not necessarily.
A woman: (unintelligible)
A man: No, no, (unintelligible) alcohol (unintelligible).
A woman: Yeah.
A man: So, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: If...
A man: (unintelligible), what's happening? (unintelligible) punish for that one. Basically, you should always be ahead.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, you can be ahead. You can always be ahead. Nobody, nobody can live a sinless life.
A man: Nobody what?
Dr. Khalifa: Nobody can live a sinless life.
Dr. Khalifa: So, but it's the end result. However, in the end, everything must be forgiven.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: A hundred times a day?
A man: 100 times a day. Dr. Khalifa: Yep.
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Sure. It's good for you.
Dr. Khalifa: God say "God loves those who continuously repent.
Dr. Khalifa: If you, if you pass by, if you pass by somebody and you're making a face and you hurt their feelings, you'd better repent, for example
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: No, if you (unintelligible) knowing... Shakira: Without knowing all this.
Dr. Khalifa: You have to know, you have know that it is... you have to be ignorant that it is Haram.
Let me read the two verses for you, in Sura 3.
God says "repentance is accepted from those who fall in sin out of ignorance and then repent immediately upon knowing that it is a sin."
So, that's when repentance is accepted.
However, if you know that gambling is Haram, and you gamble knowing that it is Haram,...
Dr. Khalifa: Parivash, these are the creatures who insisted on seeing a demonstration whether Sheytan (Satan) can make it or not.
Shakira: More clever than me?
Dr. Khalifa: So, now, God's plan begins here.
Shakira: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: God gathered them in a conference. Ok?
Here's a conference, and God told them "you bear witness that I am your Lord. Do you bear witness that I am your Lord?"
And we all said "we bear witness, we know it's a fact, You are our Lord."
Then, God put them all to death.
Dr. Khalifa: This is now, because God said "I'm gonna bring you in another life where you have no recollection of this."
Parivash: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: "You don't remember anything here. I'm gonna send you on a spaceship, spaceship Earth, far away." Parivash: Ok, the skim...
Parivash: But when they say "yeah, we are witness that You are our Lord,..."
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Shakira: Before we died.
Parivash: Ok, that means that we repent.
Dr. Khalifa: No. Shakira: No. Dr. Khalifa: No, it's a statement of fact.
Parivash: Oh, a statement of (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: God says,
Dr. Khalifa: Because, because this will be an instinct in us. Parivash: Yeah, Ok. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: So, He said "we're gonna send you to the planet Earth with this message that 'I alone am your Lord.'"
This is what God told us.
Dr. Khalifa: And then, Satan is going to tell you, give you his message on the Earth. Parivash: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: And you're going to make a choice between these two.
You either choose that God alone is your Master, or that another entity like Satan can also have authority, like Jesus, Muhammad,
Dr. Khalifa: Moses, the saints. So, this is... Parivash: Yes. Yes.
Parivash: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: This is the choice, that God alone or God and some other entity.
"God alone" is the message of God that He gave us here in this context.
God and somebody else like Muhammad or Jesus or Mary or saints is Satan's message.
What Satan is telling us "God alone is not enough."
Dr. Khalifa: "You must..." Shakira: "You need help." Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: "God has assistants, Ali and Muhammad and so on."
Parivash: "God is so..., but..."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Shakira: "God needs..."
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, now these, now these creatures were all put to death. These are jinns and humans.
Jinns and humans, they were put to death.
And then, God, on the planet earth, created the body of Adam.
This, this is the body of Adam, made from clay.
And then, God picked out one of these guys here to be assigned to this body.
And He put him... no, God created Heaven or Paradise.
And He put Adam here in Paradise.
All these creatures are dead.
Dr. Khalifa: And created Eve also from Adam, cloned her from that.
Parivash: Yeah.
A woman: Why He created Adam and Eve? So...
Dr. Khalifa: Because this was the beginning of the plan.
Dr. Khalifa: Tasneem.
Dr. Khalifa: We're trying to find the sequence of creation.
Shakira: Okay, so, Adam and Eve are...
Dr. Khalifa: So, God put in us the instinct that only God is our Lord and Master.
Ok. And then, put us all to death, humans and jinns.
And then, created the body of Adam and the body of Eve here on earth.
Dr, Khalifa: And put them in Heaven, but they were connected. The soul was connected.
Shakira: And we were all still dead?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, all of us were dead.
Shakira: Now, why did He have to create Adam and Eve to create another mistake? That's an allegory.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no, what do you mean another mistake?
Shakira: I mean, they already committed two mistakes. Now, this is the third mistake they committed.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but you see, God wants to show us how fair... Not... it's not to show us.
God is very fair and just, okay?
And He wants us to, we make the choices.
God does not want robots.
In fact, this rebellion here, the purpose of it, one of the most important
objectives, is to show all of God's creatures that we have the freedom of choice.
Dr. Khalifa: We will never know it if Satan did not rebel.
Shakira: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: You're following me? Ok. Shakira: Yes, yes, I follow.
Dr. Khalifa: So, God created the fire and He gave us the choice to use it to cook.
Shakira: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: See, see in the kitchen.
Shakira: Yes. Dr. Khalifa: We're using it to cook.
Shakira: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: But also, if you put your finger in it, it will burn.
Dr. Khalifa: So, we can use it to hurt ourselves.
Dr. Khalifa:But we have to make the decision to put our finger in the fire or to use it to cook. Parivash: Alhamdu Lillah.
Dr. Khalifa: So, here is Adam and Eve in Paradise and God gave them a law. "Do not eat from this tree."
Anytime they listen to Satan, they will go with Satan.
As long as they listen to God, they'll be in God's kingdom. So, they were in God's kingdom.
Satan came to them and said "if you eat from this tree... God forbade you from eating this tree because you'll live forever in here."
And they listened to Satan.
The minute they did that, they were sucked back into their bodies.
And their bodies became visible to them.
Dr. Khalifa: You remember those verses in the Quran? Shakira: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: But when they listened to Satan, they exposed a human flaw.
They were representing all of us. We were all here.
But the fact that they listened to Satan, showed that this is a human flaw that is in all of us,
that we will listen to Satan, sometimes.
Dr. Khalifa: So,...
Shakira: It was good they rebelled because otherwise we would still be dead.
Dr. Khalifa: That's one way of looking at it.
A woman: Otherwise there won't be Shakira.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Shakira: Yes.
Parivash: In another... We can say that all genetic, all of genetic, our genetic. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Genetically, we were all in Adam. Parivash: Genetically, yeah.
Shakira: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: All of us, we were in Adam and Eve. Shakira: That's right.
Shakira: That is the allegory. Ok. Now, it is a better understanding for me. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes.
Shakira: Do you understand now? Parivash: Yes.
Shakira: All of us are genetically represented in Adam and Eve. That is the allegory. Dr. Khalifa: Oh, absolutely.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. In Adam and Eve were the Indians, the Egyptians, the Japanese, the Iranians. Shakira: We were all, all the women are represented by Eve.
Shakira: And all the men are represented by Adam.
A woman: Why should God make so many languages?
Parivash: (unintelligible) Shakira: No, no.
Dr. Khalifa: To make life interesting. To make life interesting. Shakira: (unintelligible)
Shakira: ...all the dead souls who rebelled. A woman: Life interesting to people? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Parivash: Like there are so many fruits, different variety of color, variety of...
Dr. Khalifa: It's also one of God's powers.
Dr. Khalifa: It's a very strange thing that you can speak in Hindi and I speak in Arabic. Shakira: (unintelligible) everybody..
Dr. Khalifa: And you can say what this is. What's this in Hindi? Shakira: So, when Adam rebelled, all the men rebelled. And then Eve rebel, we all rebelled.
A woman: Cup. Dr. Khalifa: Cup?
Dr. Khalifa: In Hindi, it would be what? A woman: In Hindi? Yeah, in Hindi, I don't know. Shakira: That is the allegory. But to make it easier for people to understand.
Dr. Khalifa: What is this in Hindi?
Shakira: Cup.
A woman: In English cup, but in Hindi. Dr. Khalifa: In Hindi?
Shakira: Pyaala (प्याला)
A woman: Pyaala (प्याला) Shakira: Pyaala (प्याला)
Dr. Khalifa: I would say Finjan (فنجان).
Parivash: Finjan (فنجان). We say Fenjan (فنجان).
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Finjan (فنجان).
See, I say Finjan (فنجان). You say Pyaala (प्याला), but we understood the same thing.
A woman: But the languages are created by human beings. Dr. Khalifa: This is God's power.
Dr. Khalifa: No.
A woman: Only God... Shakira: God gave them the capacity to create. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: But everything is God's creation. Dr. Khalifa: Look, we're speaking in English.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: But... Dr. Khalifa: What is cup in Japanese?
A woman: Kappu (カップ)
Dr. Khalifa: Ha? A woman: Kappu (カップ)
Dr. Khalifa: Oh.
Dr. Khalifa: That's English.
A woman: Well, we've called it.
Dr. Khalifa: Kuppu. Ha?
A woman: Kuppu?
A woman: Kuppu? A woman: Cup.
Dr. Khalifa: Kupp.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, I see. It comes from English.
Dr. Khalifa: We need something Japanese. Ok. What is book in Japanese?
A woman: Hon (本).
Dr. Khalifa: Hon (本). Ok.
Shakira: Why are you sitting here? Because God wants you to listen.
Dr. Khalifa: See, the book in Japanese is Hon (本), in Arabic it's Kitab (کتاب), in Hindi?
Shakira: Kitaab (किताब).
Dr. Khalifa: Really?
Dr. Khalifa: We're trying to get away from it.
Parivash: Yeah. Glasses. Glasses. Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: Glasses.
Parivash: Eynak (عینک). We say Eynak (عینک) in Farsi.
Dr. Khalifa: In Hindi?
Shakira: Ainak (ऐनक).
Dr. Khalifa: Wow, look at this. There's always something in common.
Shakira: How would you say it in Japanese? A woman: Origin. There is one origin.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: They all come from that origin.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: (unintelligible) Shakira: One is a parent language and then...
Dr. Khalifa: Also, there is mixing of the languages. A woman: Yeah.
A woman: India, too. India, too, there is so many languages. But the origin of all those languages is Sanskrit. Shakira: Like Persian and Urdu are basically offshoot from parent language.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: That's why so many words will be common.
Dr. Khalifa: In Hindi, I hear the word Dunya (دنیا) (दुनिया).
Shakira: Duniya (दुनिया) is world.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. It's in Arabic, also.
Dr. Khalifa: So, there's also mixing of the languages. Shakira: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: But the languages are fantastic. Parivash: What is it in Egyptian, Eynak?
Dr. Khalifa: Nazaarat (نظارات). Nazaarat (نظارات).
Shakira: Nazaara (नज़र) means eyesight in my language. Yeah.
A woman: So, you guys can understand each other?
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, yeah. Shakira: Many words. Parivash: Many words.
A woman: Oh.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, Adam and Eve started to have children.
Shakira: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Every time a child is born, one of the souls is assigned to that child.
Shakira: I understand perfectly now.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. That's the sequence. Parivash: Mã Shã Allãh.
Shakira: Actually now, I am going to do this now.
Shakira: I'm going to say that in Adam and Eve, all of us are genetically represented. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes. Shakira: So, Adam and Eve didn't make the mistake. We all made this mistake again.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Repeat it. Shakira: Right?
Parivash: Ok.
A woman: Adam and Eve didn't do mistake?
Shakira: No, no. We are genetically represented, all the women in Eve and all the men in Adam.
So, when Adam made the mistake and Eve made the mistake, we all made the mistake because God created two people, a man and a woman.
And these two people are represented by all the men and all the women.
Dr. Khalifa: We were all in them in Heaven. Shakira: When Adam ate the apple and Eve ate the apple by Satan,
Shakira: Satan didn't distract just them. He distracted this whole, all these communities that are already disbelievers.
But God had to bring them out.
So now, we are being born in the process so that we can now, God can find out who is going to believe and who is not going to believe.
Shakira: But we are being... Dr. Khalifa: But our job here is to denounce our crime that...
Shakira: Now, we have to redeem ourselves. Dr. Khalifa: And to hold God's Absolute Authority.
Shakira: Now, we have to show to God that only God is God.
Dr. Khalifa: Here we go.
Parivash: Okay, Rashad. Yeah. Alhamdu Lillah
Parivash: I understood very perfect. Shakira: Alhamdu Lillah (unintelligible).
Shakira: Oh, very good. Now ready to (unintelligible) Parivash: Ok. I have to repeat one more. Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: Alhamdu Lillah
Parivash: When, when God asked Sheytan (Satan) to prostrate Adam, it was here,
Praivash: but already, already because... Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: It was here. Shakira: Oh, yeah.
Parivash: It was here, but, but he already because the...
Dr. Khalifa: Prostrate means, this is what it means. It means Parivash: Yeah. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: that the angels will serve the human beings. Each one of us has guards. Parivash: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Angels guarding us. So, not a scratch happens without God's will. Parivash: Yeah. Yeah.
Parivash: Yeah, yeah, I understand. But they misunderstand...
Dr. Khalifa: So, Satan, of course, said "I'm not gonna serve the human beings."
Parivash: Yeah, but they misunderstand it because they said, they hear God says "prostrate Adam, and when, okay, go down."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, even the Christians think this is the original sin.
Shakira: Oh, no. Their prostration is here. Dr. Khalifa: They think...But the original sin is here.
Parivash: Yeah. But when God said "okay, if you don't, go down." But it's from here, they didn't go down here because the first one here. Shakira: No, no. Yeah.
Shakira: With the second... No, He created Adam here because...
Shakira: No, no, Rashad. No. Dr. Khalifa: He created Adam here after they were all put to death.
Shakira: No, that step is after this.
Yes, we have to go in between now.
First, He created death, right?
Shakira: When He created death, then He made the body of Adam
Dr. Khalifa: Right here, yes, on the planet Earth. Parivash: Right here.
Shakira: Yeah, He made the body of Adam, and then He gave Adam the name.
Dr. Khalifa: So,...
A woman: What is this place, then?
Dr. Khalifa: This is like, this is like a grave, a grave for all the humans and the jinns.
Shakira: Even all the people who are not born, they are here now. Dr. Khalifa: Before we came. Before you were born, you were here.
Dr. Khalifa: Before I was born...
Shakira: So many people have yet to be born. They are all here.
Dr. Khalifa: See this line here, this waving line?
Dr. Khalifa: This is where God told Satan to fall prostrate, and the angels.
Dr. Khalifa: Fall prostrate. Shakira: No, no, no. Ok. Now,
Shakira: Now, He created death, right? Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Shakira: Now, once He created death, then He, out of clay, He made Adam.
Dr. Khalifa: Right here.
Shakira: Okay, He made him on Earth.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Shakira: Right. And here, He gave Adam the name.
Shakira: And He told... Dr. Khalifa: No. A woman: No, here.
Shakira: No. Dr. Khalifa: It's here. Yes.
A woman: Yes. Shakira: So, the body of Adam was here. Dr. Khalifa: This is, this is...
Dr. Khalifa: The body of Adam was nothing, like a piece of brick, a piece of earth. The body, this body is nothing. Shakira: Ok. Fine. So,...
Shakira: Okay, so here, He asked Satan to fall prostrate in front of Adam.
Dr. Khalifa: But first, first, He got Adam out of here, brought him to life, revived him. Adam was born. Shakira: Yes. Yeah. Right. Right. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: And Adam was connected with his body, down on Earth. Shakira: Right.
Shakira: Yeah, the body was...
Dr. Khalifa: When I went up there to the world of souls, I was connected with my body down in Mecca. Shakira: Right. Sure. Sure.
Shakira: Right. Right.
Dr. Khalifa: There were some invisible rope connecting my body to me up there. Right. Shakira: Right. To your soul. Ok. Fine.
Dr. Khalifa: The same way Adam was up here and his body was down on Earth.
Shakira: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: And then, God told the angels "you are going to serve this human race. You're going to drive the wind through them." Shakira: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: "You're going to grow the crops and the food. You're going to guard them." Shakira: Yeah.
Shakira: Yeah. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: And they all said, the angels said "yes", but Satan said "no way." Shakira: Yeah.
Shakira: So, what are the names that He gave them?
Parivash: "No way" because...
Dr. Khalifa: The names are the VCR, the TV.
Shakira: Adam gave them...
Dr. Khalifa: God gave Adam the names. Yes. Shakira: the names?
Shakira: Names, I don't understand.
Dr. Khalifa: The name of, what is this?
Shakira: Oh, He taught him the language.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. You can think of it as language. Parivash: The name of everything. Shakira: In language.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Shakira: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: The names of all things. Shakira: So,...
Shakira: And then, and then, Adam told that to the angels? Dr. Khalifa: The automobile.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, God put the angels, gave them a test.
Dr. Khalifa: He said, see, there are things I know that you don't know.
Shakira: Oh yes, I understand.
Dr. Khalifa: And one of the most important things is that God knew that some of us were swept in the crowd. Shakira: Yeah.
Shakira: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: That we didn't deserve to go to Hell.
Shakira: God taught Adam the names. That means He taught him about the universe, about the earth. Parivash: Yes. Yes.
Shakira: And then, when the angels came, he gave them the names.
And the angels fell prostrate because God told them to, but also because Adam had knowledge
Shakira: that God gave him. God gave knowledge to Adam. Dr. Khalifa: Yes, but God gave Adam certain knowledge. In other words, the angels
Dr. Khalifa: realized that some of us deserve to be served and...
Shakira: Okay, good.
Dr. Khalifa: Deserve to be redeemed.
Parivash: And this is also second of the sin of the Sheytan (Satan), too. Because the first, he said that he can be god beside God.
Dr. Khalifa: Right here. Right here.
Parivash: Yeah, here. And the second one, God said "prostrate", he didn't prostrate. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Shakira: Yeah, this time. Parivash: Yeah, this time.
Shakira: This time. So, all this happened. Parivash: And at that time, they go down.
Dr. Khalifa: In other words, he continued to be a rebel.
Parivash: Yeah, continued.
Dr. Khalifa: This is why, this is why Adam was redeemed, but Satan was not.
Because Adam said "please God, I made a mistake. Forgive me."
Dr. Khalifa: But Satan continued to think, he still thinks that he can be a god. Shakira: Yeah. Yeah.
Shakira: And (unintelligible), we did not...
Dr. Khalifa: He still thinks that he can solve it, but the things are getting out of hand. For example, look at AIDS. Parivash: Yeah.
A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Two hundred years ago, there was no AIDS. Where did AIDS come from?
Dr. Khalifa: These things are getting out of hand as far as Satan is concerned. Shakira: He created the earth after we were put to death. So, we did not witness
Dr. Khalifa: Because he's trying to rule this world without any diseases or problems, conundrums. Shakira: here. Firstly, He created death. So, we did not witness our creation.
Shakira: The angels have witnessed the creation. The angels, the mountains, and the animals, they all witnessed creation.
Shakira: But we and the jinns did not witness the...
A woman: Because we were in this. Shakira: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Creation of this universe? Shakira: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, actually, actually, nobody did.
Shakira: But I thought the angels witnessed the creation.
Dr. Khalifa: They part... Some of the angels participated in some of the creation.
But you see, if you look, I want you to read this.
Dr. Khalifa: Don't be frustrated now. She wants to learn everything at once.
Parivash: Yeah, what do you mean? Because before death, we were alive, and God put us to death.
Dr. Khalifa: No, but she's talking about the creation of the universes. Shakira: The creation of the universe.
Dr. Khalifa: Seven universes. Parivash: Oh, yeah. Yeah, seven universes. Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: Here, I want you to read... Shakira: We didn't witness the creation.
Dr. Khalifa: I want you to read this. Shakira: But that I know. But I thought that the angels witnessed the creation.
Dr. Khalifa: Wow. Here it is.
Shakira: [18:51] I never permitted them to witness the...
Dr. Khalifa: Here you go. Yes. Yes. Shakira: This I know. This I told you.
Shakira: [18:51] I never permitted them to witness the creation of the heavens and the earth, nor the creation of themselves. Nor do I permit the wicked to be members in My kingdom.* Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. Shakira: Yeah, but...
Dr. Khalifa: It's talking about Satan. Yeah, cause this...
Shakira: No, but I am talking about the angels. The angels witnessed the creation. Dr. Khalifa: See reaching to the end.
Dr. Khalifa: Some of them.
Shakira: Only some of them?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. For they participated in it. A woman: Where is it? Where is it?
A woman: Why not all?
Dr. Khalifa: Because what is God... Who is God talking about here?
Shakira: Us.
Shakira: [18:51] I never permitted them... He's talking... Dr. Khalifa: No.
Shakira: [18:50] We said to the angels,... Okay, let me, my goodness.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Shakira: [18:50] We said to the angels, "Fall prostrate before Adam." ... Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Shakira: I have to read it slowly. Parivash: Yes.
Shakira: [18:50] ... They fell prostrate, except Satan. He became a jinn, for he disobeyed the order of His Lord.* Will you choose him and his descendants as lords instead of Me, even though they are your enemies? What a miserable substitute!
Dr. Khalifa: Ok.
Shakira: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: [18:51] I never... Shakira: [18:51] I never permitted them to witness ... Dr. Khalifa: Stop, stop.
Dr. Khalifa: Who are "them"? Shakira: He means [18:50] We said to the angels,... Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Who are "them"? Yes.
Shakira: Everyone.
Dr. Khalifa: No. Go back. See.
Shakira: [18:50] ... He became a jinn, for he disobeyed the order of His Lord.* Will you choose him and his descendants ... Dr. Khalifa: That's talking... Will you choose him and his descendants...
Shakira: Ok. [18:51] I never permitted them... So, these are the jinns and his descendants. Dr. Khalifa: Yes, there you go.
A woman: descendants. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Shakira: [18:51] I never permitted them to witness the creation of the heavens and the earth, nor the creation of themselves. ...
Shakira: Oh, but I...
Dr. Khalifa: Especially that God goes on says
Dr. Khalifa: [18:51] ... Nor do I permit the wicked... Because God is talking about Shakira: [18:51] ... Nor do I permit the wicked to work in My kingdom.
Dr. Khalifa: him and his descendants. Shakira: So,
Shakira: But we, did we witness creation?
Dr. Khalifa: No. No, we didn't either.
Shakira: So, the angels, how are you... Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Some of the angels participated in the creation process because of the statement "we created."
Shakira: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: When God says "we", plural, it means the angels participated.
Dr. Khalifa: When God says "I created", it means nobody else participated. Shakira: Yeah.
Shakira: But maybe the "we" means different angels at different times, right?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Shakira: I mean, when He says "we", it might be ten billion angels in this "we", ten billion angels in another verse, we.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Shakira: Do you understand me?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, it could be different angels at different times. Shakira: So, that might...
Shakira: Right. So, it can encompass all the angels.
Dr. Khalifa: No. Because there are so many of them.
Shakira: Yeah. So, they witnessed different parts of the creation process. Dr. Khalifa: And it's not necessary.
Dr. Khalifa: Because there are so many, so many trillions. Shakira: Ok. It's immaterial, really.
Shakira: It doesn't help me at all. Dr. Khalifa: You're right.
Dr. Khalifa: But I wanted you to know that Satan and his...
Dr. Khalifa: and the jinns did not witness any creation. Shakira: the jinns. Yeah. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: God kept it from them because the verse says "I", singular. [18:51] I never permitted them to witness ...
Dr. Khalifa: And God is talking specifically about Satan and his descendants.
Parivash: Oh, it's stupid
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. No, no, it isn't. But I just worry that you may generalize beyond...
Shakira: No, I won't.
Dr. Khalifa: ...beyond the truth.
Shakira: No, I won't. I intend to, but I won't.
Dr. Khalifa: No, it's a matter of, you know, you're a scientist. Being an M.D., you're a scientist. Shakira: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: So, I'm watching your statements and I'm trying to make them scientific.
Shakira: Yeah.
Shakira: Also, I should not talk beyond the Quran. I should talk exactly... Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Exactly. Exactly the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: Any type of talk beyond the Quran will, likely will go wrong. Shakira: We're talking lies. Yeah.
Shakira: Yeah, I cannot do that.
Shakira: Okay, so this one... Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: Okay, let's go on with that.
Dr. Khalifa: So now, we've got the sequence of this.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, let me go back to 66. We didn't finish even the page.
Shakira: I know. Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Here.
[10:66] Absolutely, to GOD belongs everyone in the heavens and everyone on earth. Those who set up idols beside GOD are really following nothing. They only follow conjecture. They only guess.
So, when people...
In the newspaper everywhere, you see people thanking Saint Jude for the success of the surgery.
Dr. Khalifa: Have you seen that? Shakira: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Saint Jude is the health saint. Shakira: Saint Jude is...?
Shakira: Oh, the saint of health.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. And... so, God is saying here they were really idolizing nothing because Saint Jude is dead,
powerless, he knows nothing about the surgery, never heard of it, and probably Saint Jude himself never existed.
Shakira: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Some of those saints are fictional.
We find out now.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, so those who set up idols besides God are really following nothing.
Because even if Saint Jude is alive, he has no power over the surgery that you are doing.
Shakira: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: He has nothing to do with it.
Dr. Khalifa: So, they are following nothing. They only follow conjecture. They only guess.
[10:67] He is the One who rendered the night for your rest, and rendered the day lighted. These are proofs for people who can hear.
When you think of night and day, what are we talking about?
We're talking about the planet Earth hanging in space and rotating like this so the sunlight creates day and night.
Dr. Khalifa: Are you okay?
Shakira: Yeah, I'm getting a lot of shocks. I'm feeling, I am feeling so bad that I created the mistake. I feel like...
Dr. Khalifa: Which mistake?
Shakira: This mistake.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, I see.
Shakira: I don't want to be in this world because I am so mad. Dr. Khalifa: Well, aren't you glad you're given a chance to do that?
Dr. Khalifa: This is exactly why God brought you here. Shakira: Yeah, but it's getting too much to me.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, so you can denounce...You're denouncing it now.
Shakira: I am so shocked at these human people who are not realizing His presence. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: This was one Khutba. I have to send you the video. Shakira: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: This, I have to send you the video of this, one Khutba three weeks back.
Dr. Khalifa: The title was "How Bad the Human Being Is and How Fortunate We Are."
Shakira: I want to go on the streets and shout.
Shakira: "Listen to God. Listen to God." Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
I want to tell my mother like this "Listen to God."
Parivash: "Wake up." Dr. Khalifa: Now, cool down. Cool down.
Dr. Khalifa: Your aunt is worried about you.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. See, what I am telling her? A woman: No, why me?
Dr. Khalifa: "Cool down, Shakira." Parivash: Yeah, cool down.
Shakira: But I'm not mad. I am so stable.
A woman: No, I am not thinking anything... First, I have to know.
Shakira: No, no, but for me, I am so excited for me. A woman: And then, I have (unintelligible) I heard. That's why I am listening.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Mã Shã Allãh. She's just too enthusiastic.
A woman: She is always, I am telling, she is enthusiastic. Whatever the person is. Not only today.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: This is the big one. A woman: She's always... Yeah. Shakira: No, but not (unintelligible).
A woman: This is a big shock. This is a big shock, maybe. Dr. Khalifa: This is the real thing. Yes.
A woman: She had so many shocks before.
A woman: Yeah. Shakira: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: But this is, this is the fantastic realization.
It's where it comes with the, with the proof.
Dr. Khalifa: But I am telling her to cool down. Cool down.
A woman: Yeah.
A woman: That's, you have to make her.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Then, God... Parivash: Messenger of God tells you that you have to be cool down and...
A woman: Calm down.
Shakira: But cool down doesn't mean that I can't, Parivash: You have to obey.
Shakira: I shouldn't go out. A woman: No, no, not Parivash: No.
A woman: Not your mind. Relax. Dr. Khalifa: Relax. To relax.
Shakira: Cool down for myself so I feel better about..., right? Parivash: Relax.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Parivash: Yeah, when you talk, relax.
Dr. Khalifa: Cause not everybody is as enthusiastic as you are. A woman: See, you shouldn't be emotional in talking and everything.
A woman: Then, there will be mistakes. Parivash: Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: Yes, exactly.
A woman: You have to calm down and slowly, you have to teach people. Dr. Khalifa: Cool. Yes.
A woman: Then, only they will find... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: You do exactly what you want, only more effectively. A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Calm down is a very good thing. A woman: Yeah.
Shakira: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Calm down and see. Parivash: I was exactly like you.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. Yes. Shakira: How long now? Parivash: Yes.
Parivash: Huh? Shakira: How long it took you? Dr. Khalifa: Three, four years.
A woman: Three, four years?! My God.
Parivash: Now, I am relaxed.
Shakira: Three, four years! Parivash: Yeah, I was really hyped, you know. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Shakira: Me, too. Parivash: I went as soon as I came back from...
Dr. Khalifa: She wanted to go on the streets and shout at the people. Shakira: Me, too, all the time, you know.
Parivash: You know, you know what's happening. Every time, you know. I went to my neighbor. Shakira: Me, too.
Parivash: He's Jewish. I say "you know what's happening?"
Shakira: Ask her (unintelligible) Parivash: We are same. We are same.
Dr. Khalifa: Listen, listen, you're gonna laugh at this.
Parivash: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Somebody is in the street lost about the address. And they come and knock on her door. Parivash: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: "Is this where Mr. So-and-so", then Parivash "come in, come in. Do you know that God sent a message that it's mathematically coded?"
"And we now have proof that tells us where we're going wrong and how we can correct it and how we go to Heaven."
The woman is coming to ask about an address.
Dr. Khalifa: And this happened when I was there.
Shakira: I'm doing the same thing.
Parivash: Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: Of course. Exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: How do you think Naoko is here? Why do you think Naoko is here?
They were going in the same class studying English and Naoko came to say "how do you say this word?", for example.
And she said "did you know that God sent a message?"
And Naoko said "what?"
Parivash: Yeah but...
She said "God sent a message that's mathematically coded." Naoko said "really? What is that?"
She said "come to my house."
Dr. Khalifa: This is how it happened. Parivash: And at that time, we couldn't talk even English.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Parivash: Because it was very low class in English. We couldn't talk in English, but we understand each other.
Dr. Khalifa: And I bear witness to this. Naoko didn't know any English, and Parivash didn't know any English.
A woman: Yeah. Housekeeper, she don't know any English. I'm trying hard. But we are trying our best to contact with her. Dr. Khalifa: Communicate.
Parivash: If you want, God wants. A woman: Yeah. Yeah. Shakira: Yeah.
Parivash: Yeah but to say... Yeah. A woman: Because the heart is good, we can communicate.
Dr. Khalifa: But there's nothing wrong with you. In fact, there is something right with you. Shakira: I know but...
A woman: Yeah. Shakira: But my mother keeps telling me, and my husband keeps telling me that I have to contain myself.
Shakira: I shouldn't talk about this to anybody. I have to do it only to myself. And I should, you know,... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Parivash: Actually, my husband, he doesn't want to see any of this. A woman: They say "you need not create enemies."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Going and telling disbelievers who argue with you. Just tell. Dr. Khalifa: You made them nervous. But put on a facade of calmness.
A woman: Just tell them. Parivash: Yeah. Just tell them.
A woman: Whether they believe or not, that is God's will. Parivash: Yeah. Yeah. Just tell them.
A woman: You shouldn't force them to do... Shakira: No, but Damesh tells me I cannot talk to anybody. He says I shouldn't talk.
Shakira: He says "you should become..." A woman: No, talk (unintelligible)
A woman: Don't, don't start and create problems like you talk to your friend Piyush, and she's against you like that. Shakira: Yeah, he told me... But I didn't talk badly to her.
Shakira: That is the problem. A woman: Yeah.
Shakira: I just gave her the book, and she got upset. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Right.
Shakira: I gave her only the book. A woman: Not just book but you were arguing about these matters and she got upset and (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: She has to get upset.
Shakira: I never argued with her.
Shakira: God is my witness. A woman: Calm down. Calm down.
Shakira: I know, but I never argued with her.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, I believe that because it happens frequently.
Dr. Khalifa: Sometimes, we're just giving the message very quietly and very nicely, but they become up in arms. Shakira: Just giving the book to them. A woman & Parivash: Yeah.
A woman: Even though, I don't know here before, I was telling her.
Shakira: I don't know him, too.
A woman: Be calm down and teach them whatever you know. Let them listen or not, that's not your business. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Shakira: But...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. But what I'm saying is sometimes you can't help it. A woman: Isn't it? When the soil is,...
A woman: When the soil is fertile, the seed will grow.
A woman: The seed will germinate. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. I went though this myself.
Dr. Khalifa: Sometimes I just, in the gentlest possible way, I just give them the message and they'll become terribly upset. Shakira & a woman: Yeah.
Shakira: He's telling even if you talk nicely, people sometimes they are so fanatical... A woman: Yeah, but you should be like that.
A woman: You are a messenger, that's why you should be calm and still. You should have patience. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Exactly.
Shakira: How do I know how he was? Maybe 20 years ago, he would scream at them.
Shakira: Because (unintelligible), I don't know. But with time, so patient. 20 years, maybe 20 years from now, I will be... Dr. Khalifa: Yes. It's true. Yes.
A woman: That means there is some weakness in the messenger.
Shakira: Right? It takes time and...
Parivash: Yes.
A woman: There shouldn't be... Shakira: Even to become a messenger and become a good messenger, it takes time.
A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: It takes time. Yes.
Shakira: Yes. Parivash: God willing. IN SHAA ALLAH. A woman: Even people listening and all those,
A woman: it is their capacity to understand. Shakira: But I want to reach the majority.
Shakira: I want us to reach the majority.
Shakira: And I think a better way than to hand out this book is talking for the first time.
Dr. Khalifa: You're doing very good with those college... Shakira: That's what we should do.
A woman: And also, I want... Excuse me. Dr. Khalfia: Yes. Wonderful.
A woman: And also I want... First, you refine yourself.
A woman: Calm down.
Shakira: Aunt, I refine myself... A woman: Leave the anger and everything.
A woman: Unless you do those things first, you cannot preach or you cannot tell people. You should be the one that shows an example, isn't it?
Dr. Khalifa: Right, but you see, like I said, sometimes... A woman: If somebody (unintelligible) and says "oh, Shakira is doing like that, but she is preaching like this."
A woman: It shouldn't be like that.
Dr. Khalifa: No, did you hear... it's not what she said, that she... Shakira: First, how can I be a good Muslim the way I am.
Dr. Khalifa: All she did was give them the book. A woman: Not good Muslim, good person. You said "good person is enough." Shakira: Yes. I'm a bad person.
Dr. Khalifa: Shakira, you know, what they feel, it's the ego again. A woman: No, not that.
A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Where you're telling them that everything you were doing was wrong. A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: "Me?! Everything I was doing was wrong." A woman: Yeah. That's what creates enemies.
Dr. Khalifa: But she can be, no, but she can be very diplomatic and very nice and this will still happen.
You just show them this and it says, for example, "the first pillar of Islam is 'I bear witness that God is the only god.'"
Now, the Muslims, in 1400 years, they added, "and I bear witness that Muhammad is His messenger."
The Quran says that this is idolatry.
You should not put any name next to God.
So, what she's telling her mother is that the first pillar that she has been practicing is wrong.
And this gets them all upset.
Dr. Khalifa: And she can do this in the nicest way.
Shakira: I have done it in the nicest way. I am nice to them. A woman: Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: But it still... yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: But still upsets them because all of a sudden they realize that all their life they've been doing something wrong.
Shakira: I'm talking nicely...
Dr. Khalifa: And they don't take it in a nice way.
Shakira: I have changed so much. Really, I have changed. Dr. Khalifa: This makes them very upset.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Shakira: But what is happening is that even if I am talking to them in the nicest way, they still Dr. Khalifa: Still we know this. Yes.
Shakira: are being mean to me because they think that I am... A woman: Not mean.
Shakira: Yes, my mother is mean to me. A woman: You want suddenly to change them.
Shakira: No, I don't want to change them. A woman: The change isn't suddenly. Because you change...
Shakira: They blame me for everything.
Shakira: I don't want to suddenly change them. A woman: No, no. Not blame. Disapprove.
A woman: Your nature is you can believe whatever you believe suddenly. But everybody is not so fast. Shakira: No, my nature has nothing to do with it anymore.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. True.
A woman: You shouldn't get angry with them.
Shakira: I am not getting angry with them. They are getting angry with me. Dr. Khalifa: In fact,...
A woman: Yeah, that is also true.
Shakira: I am not getting angry with them. They are getting angry with me. A woman: But... That doesn't matter.
Shakira: I know it doesn't matter. A woman: It doesn't matter if they get angry with you.
Parivash: Yes. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A woman: But you have to be composed and you have to explain. Shakira: I am composed.
A woman: If they don't listen, that is their fate. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Shakira: What is happening is that they are being mean to me. And they are being rude to me. Dr. Khalifa: Actually, this is what keeps them. Parivash: Yes.
Shakira: But then they are again turning around and blaming me. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Parivash: But, maybe, God...
Shakira: That I have to be good when I am being good. Parivash: Yeah, but, maybe,
Parivash: this verse is for you. That this is not the time that the believers give up the disbelievers. And if... You read this the Quran? Shakira: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Parivash: Is it time for...
Dr. Khalifa: She knows it perfectly, yes, what the deal is. Parivash: You give them... yeah, Alhamdu Lillah. Mã Shã Allãh.
Shakira: But they were not... To me... I know Rashad Khalifa telling me.
But to me the verse, the believers becoming disbelievers... We were going to ask him that one.
Shakira: They were not believers to start with.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Shakira: Because even though they are people of the scripture...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Shakira: That I... Mã Shã Allãh, I hope, IN SHAA ALLAH, my mother will be guided.
Shakira: But let me take my mother for an example.
If they are talking about her, then, if she's a believer, then she became a disbeliever.
But how can she be a believer when she is already doing everything wrong?
Shakira: How can she be a believer? You can describe her as a people of the scripture. Dr. Khalifa: Ok. This is, this is here (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Surah 27...23 and 27 and 29.
Shakira: Ok. Sura... Ok. Ok. Dr. Khalifa: So, let me tell you first before you look at that.
Dr. Khalifa: Your mother sincerely believes in God.
Shakira: Sincerely. Believe me, she believes in God. Dr. Khalifa: Right. Yes.
Shakira: She talks only of one God. No question. Dr. Khalifa: You ask her no question about it.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. So, well, let's look at it. Shakira: Yes.
Shakira: I totally agree with that. My goodness, she believes in God and loves Him so much, Mã Shã Allãh, only with one little thought.
Shakira: I don't know little, but only one thought.
(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Here's one of them.
Dr. Khalifa: ...to this way? Shakira: God. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: They will say... Shakira: To God.
Dr. Khalifa: [23:85] Say, "Why then do you not take heed?"
Shakira: She says "I am taking heed."
Dr. Khalifa: No, then, she's not taking heed. It doesn't matter what she says.
If she is not doing the Shahada correct, she's not taking heed.
Shakira: This one, when I read it, it is too shallow. Dr. Khalifa: But this is what you, this is what you say. A woman: She is not taking the heed?
Shakira: No, she's not taking heed because...
Dr. Khalifa: Because the Quran... God says... Shakira: if you ask her, if you ask somebody...
Shakira: Go ahead.
Dr. Khalifa: The Quran, God says "your testimony shall be 'I testify that God alone is god.'" This is it. But they don't do that.
Dr. Khalifa: Her mother, my mother... I think my mother changed. But my father didn't.
Dr. Khalifa: My father wouldn't say "only God is god." He would say "only God is god and Muhammad is His messenger."
Shakira: He's his witness. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: So, they put Muhammad next to God. And this is going against the Quran.
A woman: Only one doubt I have. If you pray to God, if you submit to God, we can pray in the name of God. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: But it helps human beings in such a way that through somebody that we know... Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. This is where... A woman: Jesus, Muhammad. Shakira: Satan is speaking. That's be Satan.
Dr. Khalifa: This is the whole idea. A woman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: The whole idea... A woman: But up to now, God kept quiet for 1400 years, why should He... Dr. Khalifa: No, no. I'm glad you mentioned this.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Yeah. Don't go any further.
A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: This is... You put your finger now on our problem.
Dr. Khalifa: Our problem is, we think that through somebody, we can go to God. A woman: We did, up to now.
Dr. Khalifa: God doesn't want us to do that. God wants us to deal directly with Him.
Dr. Khalifa: With no in-betweens. A woman: But in the Bible, it was said,
A woman: through Jesus, you will redeem your sins Dr. Khalifa: No.
Parivash: Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: through Jesus. Dr. Khalifa: No.
A woman: Because he shed the blood for the human beings. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Not through Jesus.
Dr. Khalifa: Maybe as a teacher. Maybe.
Dr. Khalifa: But Jesus himself said, Jesus himself said "you forget any other entity and you deal directly with God."
A woman: He also said? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Yeah. But, but later, they started this. Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: That's right. It's because of Satan now.
Dr. Khalifa: So, Satan gives us his message.
Dr. Khalifa: Satan's... A woman: But there is nothing wrong through him if we pray to God.
A woman: Final is final. Final. Dr. Khalifa: Yes, there is something wrong.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Wait, why? What? Dr. Khalifa: There's something wrong.
A woman: But we have... Dr. Khalifa: Cause God wants us to be devoted to Him alone.
A woman: But see, there will be bare if you pray to God, no name, nothing. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A woman: That is the last stage, I know.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. A woman: But before that last stage, we should have something to concentrate our minds in goodness.
Dr. Khalifa: Looks like we do. Looks like we all do that. A woman: Good people or goodness.
Dr. Khalifa: In the beginning, we all go through some other person. But that's wrong. A woman: Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: And then, we... A woman: That is other person leads to, because we believe in the human being, that he is born.
A woman: And we know that our ancestors saw him, saw Jesus. Let me tell. Jesus. saw him. And He is a perfect man. Our ancestors are telling, that's why we are respecting him, too.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: And then, finally, we are praying to God. We pray God. I pray to God, Jehovah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Jehovah, but also add Jesus.
A woman: We are praying through Jesus, Jehovah. We are praying through Jesus to You. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Because he is Your son.
A woman: You sent him as a messenger. And at that time... Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Yeah. No, this is...
A woman: Prophet, prophet or messenger, whatever. Dr.Khalifa: No, this, this is... Yeah.
A woman: Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: No, this will, this will nullify our work.
Dr. Khalifa: This means we insist... because... A woman: How? How? Because he is a perfect man, we know.
A woman: Jesus is a perfect man. Dr. Khalifa: No.
A woman: No, he's not perfect? Dr. Khalifa: No, he was not a perfect man.
A woman: How?
Dr. Khalifa: He made mistakes.
A woman: Well.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A woman: About God... "I am son of God" he said. That is the mistake? Dr. Khalifa: Well, Jesus said about God.
A woman: No, the people said that he is the son of God.
A woman: Yeah, people, about people, forget. About him, what do you say? Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, if we,
Dr. Khalifa: If we understand God's Greatness, we can see the blasphemy of saying that he was God's son. A woman: But He always told
A woman: "Pray to God, I am talking because God gave me these verses and these words" and something like that.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, you see, you know what the first commandment is that Jesus repeated? A woman: But didn't mean...
A woman: Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: That it came through Moses and Jesus repeated.
Dr. Khalifa: "You shall worship God, your Lord, with all your heart, all your body, all your soul.
Dr. Khalifa: Right? You know that commandment? A woman: Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, if I worship God with all my heart, then there is no room for anybody else. A woman: Yeah. Yeah.
A woman: What Jesus did mistake? Moses?
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, you mean the mistakes that he did? A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: As a human being, he made mistakes in his life.
A woman: What mistakes?
Dr. Khalifa: Let me see.
If you read the Bible, it says that one time Jesus fell to his knees and he cried until his tears were like blood and he was asking God to forgive him.
So, why was he doing this?
Because he must have done a mistake or something. He was asking God to forgive him.
Dr. Khalifa: There are several places in the Bible where Jesus prayed to God for forgiveness.
A woman: Because he is a human being and he has to explain to the human beings, give me the power and... Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Right. Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. All humans make mistakes, including Jesus. A woman: Yeah.
A woman: That's why he prayed. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: But not that... It doesn't mean that we are... Dr. Khalifa: But even, even if he is perfect...
Dr. Khalifa: Even if he is perfect, that's good for him.
Dr. Khalifa: But what he wanted us to do is to devote ourselves to God alone.
A woman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: And to forget this through somebody business. We must deal directly with God.
A woman: But...
Dr. Khalifa: Be devoted to God alone. A woman: There's nothing bad, I'm telling, but for concentration, some people may want, because...
Dr. Khalifa: Why not concentrate on God? A woman: They have belief in Jesus because he is born and we know, but our ancestors at least...
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: Now, we are telling, if we see you perfect and we can follow you...
Dr. Khalifa: No, but see, Jesus is not even aware.
A woman: But they will also forget you after you're...
Dr. Khalifa: They will drop out. I hope so. Yeah, I hope. I don't want them to have anything to do with me.
A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: See.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm telling them... A woman: They will never forget.
A woman: They will never forget the followers. Shakira will never forget you as a messenger.
Dr. Khalifa: As a history, yes. A woman: And her
A woman: her children cannot forget.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, Reagan was the president of the United States.
A woman: But they are not
Dr. Khalifa: They will not forget him. It's history. A woman: praying to Him alone.
A woman: Ok? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Through him, to God only. What is the mistake, I am asking?
Dr. Khalifa: The mistake is that you're putting somebody with God. A woman: We are not reducing our concentration.
A woman: For the path we are choosing the right path and then going to God.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but you see, your mind, you're not thinking of God alone. You're thinking of God and Jesus.
Dr. Khalifa: For God and... A woman: And Jesus we are not adding in the same status.
Dr. Khalifa: It doesn't matter.
A woman: Yeah?
Dr. Khalifa: Still God is not alone. A woman: But through God...
Dr. Khalifa: If you invite me, if you invite me to dinner...
A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: And you tell me "Rashad, bring your servant with you."
Dr. Khalifa: You're not looking at my servant in the same status as me. But still, I cannot come to your dinner by myself. A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm not alone anymore.
Dr. Khalifa: I still have to bring my servant with me.
A woman: Is it wrong if you bring your servant to the dinner?
A woman: If I call. Dr. Khalifa: No. But. No, no, but you see, God says "the requirement for you to be redeemed to God's kingdom is to be devoted to God alone."
So, when you say God and Jesus, then God is not alone.
When you say "Rashad and his servant", I'm not invited alone.
The question is alone. Because God says "Be devoted to God alone."
Dr. Khalifa: So, when you do your prayer to God, if you think of Muhammad or Jesus or Mary or the saints...
A woman: Muhammad did any mistakes?
Dr. Khalifa: Oh yeah, oh yeah, they're documented here. Muhammad made many mistakes.
Dr. Khalifa: The mistakes?
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Huh?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: And they have all these stories.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, lots of stories.
A woman: And it said that once, Jesus (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: He was dead, right?
A woman: No, no, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: That happened. Yes, yes, it's true. It's true.
A woman: And (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes
A woman: And they couldn't get it (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, it's true. God tells us this in the Quran, also.
A woman: Oh, yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: He even caused a dead person to come back to life by God's power.
See, God gave every prophet and every messenger certain signs to prove that he is God's messenger.
Dr. Khalifa: And Jesus' signs were that he healed the sick and revived even the dead, brought them back to life.
A woman: That is true...
Dr. Khalifa: But this is not Jesus' power, it's God's power.
A woman: Jesus (unintelligible) Jesus get up and (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: No, Jesus is dead.
A woman: But then, how come people started saying (unintelligible)
A woman: (unintelligible) A woman: But in some scriptures...
Dr. Khalifa: No, he has not risen.
A woman: When (unintelligible) the power and the understanding of the holy spirit.
Dr. Khalifa: No, that's wrong, yeah.
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: Holy Spirit means our own...
Dr. Khalifa: And that is wrong. A woman: our own spirit.
A woman: Holy Spirit, Padre.
A woman: No, Son... God, Son and Holy Spirit means that is our soul, I think.
Dr. Khalifa: No, they think of the Holy Spirit as the inspiration that comes from God.
A woman: Yeah, for everybody the inspiration comes through us. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: That is the spirit.
A woman: (unintelligible) that only Christians (unintelligible) go to Heaven.
A woman: Every religion says that. Dr. Khalifa: That's not right, either.
A woman: Every religion says that. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: (unintelligible) A woman: Through, through me only, through me only, through this religion only, you will go. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: That is (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: We don't, we don't say it here.
Dr. Khalifa: Not, not here.
Dr. Khalifa: This is anyone who is devoted to God. A woman: Yeah. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: This is why I made it the theme of this translation here.
A woman: I hope you would have composed this, joining all the religions.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, this is exactly what I'm doing.
A woman: But you are telling "don't pray to prophet Muhammad and don't pray to Jesus."
A woman: We are praying through them to God, not praying directly to them. Dr. Khalifa: But God doesn't want that, they don't want that either.
Dr. Khalifa: Muhammad and Jesus, they don't want us to pray through them.
Dr. Khalifa: They don't, because it's very clear...
A woman: But you cannot compose all these religions as one religion.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: They are getting against, because they are used to (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: No. No.
Dr. Khalifa: God will do that. God will unite them into one religion.
A woman: Because there are too many religions, for my question I am telling, I can't read Arabic or... Dr. Khalifa: What does... Yes. Let us take... Yes. Right.
A woman: I can read...
Dr. Khalifa: Let us take 10 religions. OK. Islam, Christianity, Judaism, Hinduism, Buddhism, Zoroastrianism, Mormon, and so on. A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: What do they have in common that unites all of them?
A woman: All those principles that God spreads.
Dr. Khalifa: But there is one thing in common.
A woman: That is common. In every religion it is common. Dr. Khalifa: Which is?
A woman: But the ways and means they are praying to God are different. Exactly. Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. Exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: So, the one thing they have in common is God. A woman: Why don't God...
Dr. Khalifa: The one thing they have in common is God. A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: All of them worship God. A woman: prayer. God.
A woman: And everything. Submission. Dr. Khalifa: Right. Right.
A woman: Perfect people are submitting in all the religions. Dr. Khalifa: But the difference...
A woman: They are, truthfully, they are praying whatever they believe. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: So, why are they fighting with each other?
A woman: Yeah. That is all men's creation, people's creation. Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. Right.
Dr. Khalifa: So, the difference... A woman: All these religions and all that.
Dr. Khalifa: The differences are the men.
Dr. Khalifa: These are the differences. Because the Christians... A woman: But I think, why not, why not people...
A woman: But they are fighting I know.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm answering your question. Here is the answer to your question. A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: All these religions, 10 of them, they have one thing in common and that is God. All of them worship God. A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Once they move away from God to the human factor, they become enemies.
Dr. Khalifa: Because the Muslims say "Muhammad is better than Jesus." A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: And the Christians say "Jesus is better than Muhammad." Then, they start to be different.
Now, if they forget Jesus and Muhammad and concentrate on the one common thing which is God, they'll be united.
Dr. Khalifa: And this is exactly how God is going to do it in the next hundred years.
A woman: Yeah, that is perfectly, I believe in that. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Right.
Dr. Khalifa: It's this. IN SHAA ALLAH. Yes. A woman: I believe in that when that time comes. I believe in that.
Dr. Khalifa: God willing.
A woman: But all the way, there are so many problems because those people are entirely fixed to that religion.
A woman: These people are entirely established. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: Why should God give so much, so much time for them to establish like that? Dr. Khalifa: But now, you know why, you know why they are different now?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: That is yhy should God do like that?
A woman: Because it is not a human being's mistake. Dr. Khalifa: You know...
A woman: They are following their ancestors. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A woman: Their ancestors taught them. Dr. Khalifa: That's wrong. We should not follow our ancestors.
Dr. Khalifa: See? A woman: But, but God gave the chance to do that.
Dr. Khalifa: No, but God is telling them here "do not follow your ancestors." A woman: Yeah.
A woman: Yeah. Then,...
Dr. Khalifa: It says "use your own mind and devote yourself to God alone."
Ok. If you pray, if you pray through Jesus and I pray through Muhammad, then we are different.
A woman: But my son is dead. Maybe, he prayed in his own God.
A woman: No name, nothing. He doesn't believe in any... Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Perfect. If he
Dr. Khalifa: If he is praying to God alone, you pray to God alone, not through anybody. And then, If I am praying to God alone, there will be no difference between us. A woman: Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: But if you pray... A woman: Yeah, but if he is not coming out and preaching and telling people like that, is it a sin?
A woman: Is it a sin? Dr. Khalifa: No, it's not a sin.
A woman: No, it is not sin. Dr. Khalifa: But it's not as much credit.
A woman: Yeah. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Not as much credit. A woman: But God knows and he knows what credit God gives him.
A woman: He wants that much credit only and he is serving the people as a doctor.
A woman: He's serving the people as their doctor. That is his duty he is thinking. And he is praying to God directly.
A woman: What about this? Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but it is not wrong to tell the people to worship God either. A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: It's not wrong to tell the people, try to save their souls, not just their bodies.
Dr. Khalifa: The soul is more important than the body. A woman: Yeah, but... but, but about...
A woman: Some people like this, there are. Do you think that they are doing sin? You had to compromise with him. Because there is nothing wrong with him.
Dr. Khalifa: With who?
A woman: With my son, I'm telling an example. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, I'm sure there isn't. A woman: He's serving the human beings as a profession.
A woman: He is graduated and he wants to do that job perfectly. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Not wrong with that. Yes. A woman: He devotes much time for that job because God created him like that.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: And he wants to do that job. He thinks like that.
A woman: "Let me do this perfectly. And let me pray to God." That's all he's doing.
Dr. Khalifa: That's fine. Yeah. Nothing wrong with that. Yeah. A woman: There is nothing wrong with him.
A woman: She should compromise with him and she has to be nice with him. And... Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: Yes, absolutely.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. I was telling her this morning. A woman: Absolutely. But while he is telling, don't create problems to the family. Is it wrong?
A woman: Is it wrong in telling that? Dr. Khalifa: No. It is wrong to create problems.
A woman: Yeah. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: He's telling, that's what he's telling. Already we had problems before. Dr. Khalifa: Right. Yes.
A woman: And you are starting this, telling people who are friendly to you so much.
A woman: And they're all getting against... Dr. Khalifa: Because she loves them.
Dr. Khalifa: She loves them. She wants them, she wants to save their souls.
Dr. Khalifa: Because you see, we were doing... A woman: Yeah, she likes...
A woman: But she should think of her husband, too.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: First, she should think of her husband first. Dr. Khalifa: Yes, definitely.
A woman: And then, think of the society later. First,... Dr. Khalifa: Right.